<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Haonan Zhuang&#39;s Blog</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-02-18T16:17:20.067Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Haonan Zhuang</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>黑龙江返岗人员两天跑近十趟办&quot;返程证明&quot;</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/19/%E9%BB%91%E9%BE%99%E6%B1%9F%E8%BF%94%E5%B2%97%E4%BA%BA%E5%91%98%E4%B8%A4%E5%A4%A9%E8%B7%91%E8%BF%91%E5%8D%81%E8%B6%9F%E5%8A%9E%E8%BF%94%E7%A8%8B%E8%AF%81%E6%98%8E%20/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/19/%E9%BB%91%E9%BE%99%E6%B1%9F%E8%BF%94%E5%B2%97%E4%BA%BA%E5%91%98%E4%B8%A4%E5%A4%A9%E8%B7%91%E8%BF%91%E5%8D%81%E8%B6%9F%E5%8A%9E%E8%BF%94%E7%A8%8B%E8%AF%81%E6%98%8E%20/</id>
    <published>2020-02-18T16:07:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-18T16:17:20.067Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><font size="0.5"><a href="https://news.sina.com.cn/s/2020-02-18/doc-iimxxstf2386206.shtm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">来源</a></font><br><font size="0.5">能不能别搞这些形式主义？吐了</font><br><font size="0.5">视察？还有那社区委员会主任</font><br><font size="0.5">这股官僚气息真是令人作呕</font><br></BR></p><p>她必须经过两个关卡，一是设在县内城镇内的关卡，由公检法的人员轮流值班，用车辆以及一些草垛把路堵上了。出入需要工作证或者县里限量发行的通行证。然后还有一道关，设在上高速的路口。如果没有相关证明的话，也上不了高速。而出城的关卡和高速关卡之间有一段很长的路。也就是说，如果你出了城，但没有拿到上高速的证明的话，你就只能在这个空白地方呆着，无法返城。</p><p>为了防止半路遇阻，何女士计划自己到各个出入关卡那里问情况、探探路。但要出去看一趟并不容易。“出城关卡的人建议我先去社区开个证明，让我可以在高速关卡问完情况后能够返回来入城。”</p><p>但社区工作人员回复说，“开不了证明，这个没法儿开，你要想出去我就给出城关卡打电话，你随时可以出去，但只要你出去你就再进不来”。何女士问，“那上高速究竟需要什么证明？”工作人员说高速已经封了。</p><p>“我继续追问该社区工作人员如果必须出高速要办什么证明，他说那你就得去做体检”。何女士又打了交通部门的电话咨询，回复说随便找一个卫生所去做就行，不要去大医院，她认为这可能也是担心大医院有危险。但她随后发现，步行范围内可到达的卫生所都没有开门。</p><p>再次回到社区，何女士得到的回复却是必须去县里的人民医院做检查。“我当时一听就很着急，人民医院这种地方，各种病患参杂的，去这种地方不是增加传染风险吗？”争论了半天，最后社区委员会主任口气强硬地对何女士重复了一遍，“你要不开这个（体检证明）的话，我可以让你现在出去，但是，我保证你上不了高速你也回不来，你自己想清楚！”</p><p>何女士和先生考虑一下，认为政策肯定会越来越严，于是当天下午四五点钟左右，两人步行40分钟，到县里的人民医院做了CT和采血，这是何女士30多年的人生中第一次拍CT，原因却不是因为生病，而是为了证明没有生病，她提起来觉得挺讽刺的，因为谁都知道X光对身体有危害。做完检查，何女士与医生沟通很久才得以拿到“没有相关症状”签字和盖章的诊断证明。</p><p>但何女士在人民医院医生开的证明后来并没有用上。因为就在她本以为所有返程准备都做完了时，当晚县里又出了一份离乡细则，对出行提出明确要求：第一，先要到居委会和街道去填一个离境申请表，并贴一张一寸照片。盖章批了以后，再去指定的医院自费检查，并由该医院出具一张专门的确认你身体健康的表格，这两个单子齐全以后方可离县。虽然何女士提前做了CT和验血等检查，但还需要填申请单、去指定的医院重新开专门的健康证明。</p><p>“我们手上并没有一寸照片，只好拿手机拍了一个，然后找熟人帮着打印了出来。”何女士说，当她拿着申请单去社区盖章时，正巧碰到相关领导来视察工作，由于离京申请表需要盖的章在领导们开会的会议室，所以所有人员拿着表格在外面等了40分钟。等领导们开完会带着口罩出来后，下一个视察环节又开始了，大喇叭广播要求大家都回去，因为无人机要开始喷洒消毒液。</p><p>拿到了所有证明的何女士不敢耽搁，第二天开车到了M市，凭机票信息和身份证正常登机回到北京，一路上十分顺利，除了核对机票信息、身份信息、查体温，并没有用到以上所有的证明。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sina.com.cn/s/2020-02-18/doc-iimxxstf2386206.shtm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;来源&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="-news" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/news/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2月8号的经济学人杂志与新冠肺炎有关的文章整理</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/2%E6%9C%888%E5%8F%B7%E7%9A%84%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%9D%82%E5%BF%97%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E6%9C%89%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0%E6%95%B4%E7%90%86/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/2%E6%9C%888%E5%8F%B7%E7%9A%84%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%9D%82%E5%BF%97%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E6%9C%89%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0%E6%95%B4%E7%90%86/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T18:40:57.362Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T19:01:04.337Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><font size="0.5">来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020</font><br>从2月8号的经济学人杂志摘录了一些与此次新冠肺炎有关的文章</p><h2 id="The-world-this-week"><a href="#The-world-this-week" class="headerlink" title="The world this week"></a><a href="https://wintersakurako.github.io/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/The%20world%20this%20week/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The world this week</a></h2><h2 id="Under-observation"><a href="#Under-observation" class="headerlink" title="Under observation"></a><a href="https://wintersakurako.github.io/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Under%20observation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Under observation</a></h2><h2 id="Keep-out"><a href="#Keep-out" class="headerlink" title="Keep out"></a><a href="https://wintersakurako.github.io/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Keep%20out/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Keep out</a></h2><h2 id="Chaguan-A-people’s-war"><a href="#Chaguan-A-people’s-war" class="headerlink" title="Chaguan | A people’s war"></a><a href="https://wintersakurako.github.io/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Chaguan%20%20A%20people%E2%80%99s%20war/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chaguan | A people’s war</a></h2><h2 id="Run-don’t-walk"><a href="#Run-don’t-walk" class="headerlink" title="Run, don’t walk"></a><a href="https://wintersakurako.github.io/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Run,%20don%E2%80%99t%20walk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Run, don’t walk</a></h2><h2 id="A-train-of-troubles"><a href="#A-train-of-troubles" class="headerlink" title="A train of troubles"></a><a href="https://wintersakurako.github.io/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/A%20train%20of%20troubles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A train of troubles</a></h2><h2 id="Viral-injections"><a href="#Viral-injections" class="headerlink" title="Viral injections"></a><a href="https://wintersakurako.github.io/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Viral%20injections/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Viral injections</a></h2>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;0.5&quot;&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;从2月8号的经济学人杂志摘录了一些与此次新冠肺炎有关的文章&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;The-world-this-week&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Th
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Viral injections</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Viral%20injections/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Viral%20injections/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T18:35:59.651Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T18:38:00.109Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020<br><br><br><font color="red"><b>China’s economy</b></font><br><font size="5"><b>Viral injections</b></font></p><p><font size="0.5">SHANGHAI </font><br><b>Companies warn of an economic crisis as China battles an epidemic</b></p><p>Rarely have plans in China fallen apart so swiftly and so publicly. On January 12th the leaders of Hubei declared that the province’s GDP would grow by 7.5% this year. They made no mention of a new virus fast spreading through its towns and cities. But less than two weeks later it could not be ignored. They placed the province under quarantine, hemming in over 50m people and rendering this year’s ﬂashy growth target almost certainly unreachable. </p><p>The lurch from conﬁdence to anxiety has echoed throughout China. In the months before the coronavirus outbreak, the stockmarket had rallied and businesses had been upbeat, not least because China and America had struck a trade deal. But optimism has crumbled as oﬃcials have begun to ﬁght the epidemic. </p><p>The Chinese stockmarket has fallen by 10% since January 20th. Factories and ofﬁces were supposed to reopen in recent days after the new-year holiday. Most provinces have ordered them to stay shut until at least February 10th. Farmers have warned that their chickens might starve because roadblocks have snarled their feed supplies. Few people dare venture out, hitting restaurants and hotels especially hard. In an interview that attracted much attention before being censored, the founder of Xibei, a restaurant chain, said that if the lockdown persisted for a few months, vast numbers could lose their jobs. “Wouldn’t that be an economic crisis?” he asked. </p><p>Analysts have rushed to lower their economic forecasts. The consensus had been that GDP would expand about by 6% yearon-year in the ﬁrst quarter. Now several expect a 4% pace, the slowest since China began publishing quarterly ﬁgures in 1992. </p><p>Usually, the further into the future you peer, the greater the uncertainty. But as past epidemics have shown, China’s oﬃcials can be fairly conﬁdent that growth will rebound to its pre-virus trajectory next year. It is the next couple of months that are the black hole. Three unknowns cloud the outlook: how long it takes to contain the virus; when the government relaxes its heavy-handed restrictions on daily life; and how long after that people resume the whirl of activity that normally makes the Chinese economy so vibrant. </p><p>This near-term uncertainty presents a challenge for economic policy. Even if growth plummets, a big stimulus package might be dangerous medicine. Given the lag in spending, the boost from projects announced today could kick in just as the economy gathers steam of its own, leading to overheating. Instead, measures to help people and ﬁrms through the rough patch are more sensible. These can be pared back when the recovery eventually arrives. Getting them right, though, is not easy. </p><p>Oﬃcials are combining temporary cash support with market interventions and forbearance. On February 3rd the central bank injected 1.2trn yuan ($172bn) into the ﬁnancial system by purchasing treasury bonds from banks that promise to buy them back within 14 days. Banks will probably suﬀer from rising loan defaults in the coming weeks; this gives them more cash to work with in the near term. The central bank can extend the supportif needed. </p><p>Oﬃcials are also meddling in the stockmarket (or, as they would say, managing it). Regulators have told brokers to bar clients from short selling, so as to limit downward pressure, according to Reuters. State media have also played cheerleader, saying that big state-owned insurance companies were primed to scoop up undervalued stocks. Share prices still dropped by 8% on February 3rd. But that was largely a catch-up with the Hong Kong market, which had been open the previous week. Trading has since stabilised, suggesting that the tactics are working. </p><p>Finally, oﬃcials have been orchestrating forbearance on various fronts. Shanghai was due to raise companies’ social-security contributions on April 1st. That has been delayed by three months, saving ﬁrms an estimated 10bn yuan. In Beijing oﬃcials have encouraged landlords to cut their commercial tenants’ rents, in exchange for subsidies. And regulators have called on banks nationwide to roll over loans to companies that would otherwise lack the cash buﬀers to survive. </p><p>Even as the death toll mounts, some ofﬁcials are already thinking about the economic distortions that have arisen in the course of the battle against the epidemic. Hospitals face shortages of masks, gowns and gloves. At the government’s urging, producers have increased output. But as Liu Shangxi, an adviser to the ﬁnance ministry, has noted, they will suﬀer from severe overcapacity after the crisis passes. The government should thus be ready, he argues, to compensate them. </p><p>Such proposals are a far cry from the bold plans that Hubei’s leaders laid out only a few weeks ago. Yet the priority these days is not to gee up growth but to ensure that society remains stable as the quarantines drag on. China’s grim new reality is that everything, even economic policy, revolves around beating the virus.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;China’s economy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Viral injections&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A train of troubles</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/A%20train%20of%20troubles/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/A%20train%20of%20troubles/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T18:33:28.472Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T18:34:54.475Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020<br><br><br><font color="red"><b>Hong Kong’s economy </b></font><br><font size="5"><b>A train of troubles</b></font></p><p><font size="0.5">HONG KONG </font><br><b>A giant ﬁnancial centre, with a currency peg, faces social unrest, a trade war and now the coronavirus. Just how stable is Hong Kong’s economy?</b></p><p>“I wanted travellers to arrive and know exactly which city they were in,” wrote Andrew Bromberg, an architect, to explain his design for West Kowloon station, where high-speed trains arrive in Hong Kong from mainland China. The platforms are deep underground, but passengers can enjoy the city’s skyline through 4,000 glass panes suspended from the station’s tilted roof. The more adventurous can go up to the rooftop for a better view. </p><p>But not anymore. The station and its rooftop are cordoned oﬀ. Four of the 21people in Hong Kong that have been infected with the Wuhan coronavirus arrived in the city by high-speed rail. The station has now been closed, alongside ten of the other 13 entry points from the mainland. </p><p>These closures may or may not slow the spread of the disease. But they will certainly hamper an economy already debilitated by months of ﬁerce anti-government protests. Figures released on February 3rd showed that GDP shrank by 2.9% year-onyear in the last quarter of 2019, when the protests reached a peak. Worse may be to come. Analysts at UBS, a bank, expect a fall of over 6% in the ﬁrst quarter of this year compared with the same period last year. </p><p>In other economies rocked by the virus, such as mainland China, Thailand and Singapore, the central bank has let the currency depreciate, easing ﬁnancial conditions. But Hong Kong is diﬀerent. Its currency has been tied to the American dollar since 1983 and conﬁned to a narrow trading band of hk$7.75–7.85 to the dollar since 2005. If it falls to the weak side, the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) is obliged to sell as many American dollars as people want to buy for hk$7.85. That has stopped the currency falling further (see chart). </p><p>But will it always do so? Even before the protests erupted or the virus mutated, some observers began to wonder if the peg would endure. According to Hong Kong’s mini-constitution, its autonomy and even the existence of its own currency is guaranteed only until 2047, which is within the duration of a 30-year mortgage. Hong Kong, many fear, is destined to become just another Chinese city—and they do not have their own currencies. Even if it remains semi-detached politically, its economy is increasingly attached to China’s. Why should its ﬁnancial conditions remain tethered to America’s? </p><p>In the forward-looking world of ﬁnancial markets, that question leads naturally to another: if Hong Kong’s currency regime is destined to change some day, how hard would Hong Kong ﬁght for it today, if the markets tested its will? Such a test is not too hard to envisage. In December, property prices fell by 1.7%, compared with the previous month, and are now almost 5% below their peak. If those falls gained momentum, speculative capital might quit the market and the city. A collapse in property prices would also test the banking system. Its assets are worth 845% of Hong Kong’s GDP (although only 30% of its total loans are spent on Hong Kong property develop ment or home purchases). And many of the deposits on the other side of its balancesheet are held by non-residents, who might prove ﬂighty in a crisis. </p><p>According to its defenders, Hong Kong’s currency peg is “virtually impregnable”. The HKMA’s foreign-exchange reserves amount to $440bn, twice as much as the money supply, narrowly deﬁned to include banknotes and the banks’ claims on the monetary authority. The banks would run out of Hong Kong dollars before it ran out of American ones. </p><p>Why then is it only “virtually” impregnable? For one thing, there are broader deﬁnitions of money supply. A war chest of $440bn may be large compared with banks’ deposits at the HKMA. But it is small compared with customers’ deposits with banks (hk$6.9trn, equivalent to $880bn). If every depositor wanted to convert their holdings into American dollars, there would not be enough to go around. </p><p>Such conversions would also have broader economic implications. Every Hong Kong dollar sold to the monetary authority disappears. All else equal, it then becomes dearer for the banks to borrow the diminishing number of Hong Kong dollars that remain. These high interest rates make holding the currency more lucrative and short-selling it more costly. But insofar as households and ﬁrms still need to borrow in Hong Kong dollars, these high interest rates also hurt the economy. How much pain would Hong Kong be willing to take? </p><p>The peg’s downfall may be imaginable. But is it probable? One place to look is the options market, where investors can hedge against the risk of the currency moving outside the band. For about 40% of the period from June 2005 to July 2018, option prices implied that the odds of the peg breaking were above 10%, suggests a recent study by Samuel Drapeau, Tan Wang and Tao Wang of Shanghai Jiao Tong University. But for most of that time markets were betting on the currency strengthening past hk$7.75 to the dollar, not weakening past hk$7.85. </p><p>Bearish bets became more popular last year during the worst of the protests. But the speculation was not as ﬁerce as it had been in 2016, after China clumsily devalued the yuan. Capital outﬂows picked up in the third quarter of last year, diminishing Hong Kong’s foreign-exchange reserves. But reserves have stabilised since, helped by a truce in the trade war between America and China. Hong-Kong dollar deposits are lower than they were six months ago, but still higher than they were a year ago. </p><p>Any signs of sustained capital outﬂows are, then, “embryonic”, says Alicia Garcia Herrero of Natixis, a bank. If capital is leaving, its speed of departure is reminiscent of one of Hong Kong’s quaint trams, not one of its bullet trains.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hong Kong’s economy &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;A train of troubl
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Run, don’t walk</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Run,%20don%E2%80%99t%20walk/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Run,%20don%E2%80%99t%20walk/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T18:30:04.062Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T18:32:25.914Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020<br><br><br><font color="red"><b>Coronavirus </b></font><br><font size="5"><b>Run, don’t walk</b></font></p><p><b>Scientists are racing to produce a vaccine for the latest coronavirus. Even if they are too late for this outbreak, their work will not be wasted</b></p><p>In recent weeks searches on Google for “contagion movie” have soared. In the ﬁlm, a thriller from 2011, a virus spreads rapidly around the world, killing 26m people. The plot follows the frantic eﬀorts of scientists to produce a vaccine. Some 133 days after the ﬁrst infection, they succeed. </p><p>In the real world most recent vaccines have taken years to develop. Some have taken more than a decade. Others, such as a vaccine to stop HIV, the virus that causes aids, still elude scientists. But technological innovations and a more streamlined development process could dramatically shrink the time it takes to produce a vaccine against a new pathogen that has the potential to cause an epidemic. </p><p>The new coronavirus that emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan in December presents vaccine-makers with an urgent test. It has so far killed almost 600 people and infected more than 28,000. Scientists in China published the Wuhan virus’s genetic sequence on January 12th, less than a week after they isolated the bug from a patient suﬀering from a mysterious respiratory infection. By late January, several groups around the world had started work on a vaccine using these genetic data. The ﬁrst clinical tests on humans, for safety, could begin as early as April. With luck, a vaccine could be ready within a year. Next week the World Health Organisation (who) will convene a global meeting to set a research agenda. It will agree on rules, or protocols, for trials and work out which medical advances should be priorities. </p><p>People have rushed to make new vaccines before. The west African Ebola outbreak of 2013-16 tested the world in many ways, but particularly in the need to speed up the delivery of new treatments. Organisations and institutions that normally work slowly, and at arm’s length, came together to get the job done faster. Drug regulators from America and Europe, pharmaceutical ﬁrms, charities, experts and the who all worked closely to advance the trials and technologies needed. They succeeded. An outbreak of Ebola in 2018 in the Democratic Republic of Congo, which now appears to be on the wane, has been contained largely as a result of the wide availability of a vaccine. This process of scientific acceleration is under way again, this time “on steroids”, says Seth Berkley, the boss of gavi, a vaccine-ﬁnance agency. </p><p>Even if a vaccine were ready within a year, it would be too late to stem the current epidemic in China. But it could help other countries. Fears are growing that the Wuhan virus will spread more widely and become an established seasonal disease around the world, like the common ﬂu. China’s extraordinary eﬀorts to contain the virus, including quarantining over 50m people, may stave oﬀ epidemics in other countries until next winter. It is too soon to tell how deadly the Wuhan virus is. But if it is at least as bad as seasonal ﬂu, a vaccine for those most at risk will be vital. In 2017-18 more than 800,000 people were hospitalised and about 60,000 died in America alone as a result of inﬂuenza. </p><p>The rush to develop a vaccine against the Wuhan virus has been led by the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovation (CEPI), a group set up in 2017 in the wake of the west African Ebola outbreak. CEPI’s purpose is to forearm the world against future outbreaks of disease, without knowing what those diseases will be. Its aim is to have a vaccine against a previously unknown pathogen ready to test in humans within 16 weeks of its identiﬁcation. To that end, some of the university research centres and biotechnology ﬁrms that it has funded have been working on “plug-and-play” vaccine design and manufacturing technologies that can be used for a number of pathogens. This allows the genetic sequence of a particular pathogen to be slotted into an existing molecular platform that forms the basis of the vaccine. </p><p>In the past, laboratory work on a vaccine required stocks of the actual virus. It would be treated to make it harmless but still able to tickle the immune system into producing antibodies—proteins that ﬁght oﬀ the wild virus if it attacks. Working with a deadly virus is tricky, naturally. It requires special containment facilities and exhaustive procedures to prevent it from escaping or infecting scientists. </p><p>Gene sequencing has made this process quicker, safer and easier. Researchers can build synthetic versions of parts of viruses to work on vaccines without needing complete samples of the pathogens. </p><p>Scientists have produced vaccines against other viruses, including Zika, Ebola and two other coronaviruses—sars(Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome) and mers (Middle East Respiratory Syndrome)—using such technology. The vaccine research on these two cousins of the Wuhan virus has come in handy in recent weeks.</p><br><b>Going viral</b><p>Once a vaccine has been developed in a laboratory, it is sent to a factory where it is turned into a sterile vaccine mix. This is then put into vials and tested to ensure it is not contaminated before clinical trials in humans can be carried out. Many of these tests are done in petri-dishes; the process takes several months. Genetic sequencing can do the job much faster. By sequencing the dna of everything in a vial of vaccine and examining the result, scientists can spot traces of viruses that should not be present. Vaccine research groups in Britain are in talks with the country’s medicines regulator about an approval process for such alternative testing methods. </p><p>The development of a vaccine can be speeded up if bottlenecks in the process are eliminated, says Sarah Gilbert. She leads a group at Oxford University which is working on a vaccine against the Wuhan virus. Her group has developed a template for vaccines that can be adapted quickly for new pathogens. The researchers can make the ﬁrst small quantities of a new vaccine in just six to eight weeks. In the past the process would have taken up to a year. The other groups trying to come up with a vaccine for the Wuhan virus are using similar methods involving templates that have already been proven to work. </p><p>Faster regulatory approval can also speed vaccines through clinical trials. Even as it started making the vaccine, Dr Gilbert’s group began putting together an application for clinical trials for it. The group plans to apply for an expedited ethical and regulatory review, which can be granted within days as it was for clinical trials of the Ebola vaccine conducted in Britain in 2014. Normally, the process takes about three months, says Dr Gilbert. </p><p>Even if a vaccine is developed and approved, the rapid rise in cases of the Wuhan virus in China and its spread to other countries has created a new urgency: planning ahead for ways to make massive quantities of a vaccine quickly. There are not many factories that can mass-produce vaccines, so new vaccines often wait in a long queue. Aware of this problem, the American government has built dedicated manufacturing facilities that can produce vaccines rapidly for emergencies. Britain is doing something similar. </p><p>When CEPI was planning its work, those involved were thinking about epidemics (outbreaks limited to one country), not pandemics (global epidemics), explains Richard Hatchett, the head of the group. Last week CEPI put out a call for vaccine candidates for the Wuhan virus that can be manufactured on a large scale with existing capacity. On February 3rd it brought on board as a partner GSK, a big drug ﬁrm, which has agreed to lend its highly eﬀective adjuvant to a new vaccine. An adjuvant is a special ingredient that makes vaccines more eﬃcient by boosting the immune response—which means that fewer doses of the vaccine or a lower concentration of its core ingredient is needed for vaccination. </p><p>Even if a vaccine can be produced in sufﬁcient quantities, getting it to the people who need it, regardless of where they live, can still be a problem. In theory, a vaccine for the Wuhan virus would go to those most at risk, such as health workers, the elderly and those with conditions that appear to make the virus more lethal, such as patients with immune deﬁciencies. The problem is that politics often intervenes during a pandemic, and governments that are the home to vaccine-making facilities can requisition some of it for their own use, citing national defence or security. </p><p>This is a problem Mr Hatchett knows all too well; he worked at the White House on medical preparedness during a ﬂu pandemic in 2009. The outbreak had a very low mortality rate, but exporting any vaccine before it was available to American citizens quickly became a vexed issue. Mr Hatchett is working with the who to try to ensure that the Wuhan virus vaccine is made at a number of diﬀerent sites around the world including ones in small countries which would quickly be able to meet the needs of their entire populations.</p><br><b>A jab in the dark</b><p>The issues surrounding any potential vaccine make questions about medicines to treat those who have become gravely ill particularly acute. Licensed medicines to treat coronaviruses do not currently exist, but experimental drugs are in development, with some early data on their use. One that has been highlighted as promising is called remdesivir, which is made by Gilead, a drug ﬁrm. Two randomised controlled trials will start enrolling patients in mid-February. Remdesivir was developed to treat Ebola but in laboratory tests has been shown to be eﬀective against a range of viruses. A combination of two drugs usually used in hiv treatment also looks promising and is already being tried on patients, says Vasee Moorthy who helps set research and development priorities at the WHO during epidemics. </p><p>Randomised controlled trials—in which some people are given the drug being tested and some are given a placebo— are the gold standard of scientiﬁc evidence. These will probably go ahead in the coming weeks when it is clear which drugs seem most promising. Trials with hospitalised patients will probably involve a placebo arm. Everyone in the trial would receive intensive care but some would also be given the drug being tested. This is because no one yet knows whether the new drugs, which may have side eﬀects, do more harm than good. The most gravely ill patients may also be allowed to try untested drugs. </p><p>Only so much preparation is ever possible in advance of a new disease. A drug or vaccine’s eﬃcacy can only be tested during an outbreak. The urgency behind the search for treatments for the Wuhan virus is understandable. Such eﬀorts were eﬀective in the case of Ebola. People are willing to rush vaccines and drugs into use for a disease with a fatality rate around 70%, as Ebola’s was. The calculus is diﬀerent for one that kills 2% (or less) of those infected. Should hasty decisions lead to products that are not completely safe, people’s faith in vaccines could be damaged. If so, the harm done to the world’s health could rival the worst feared of the Wuhan virus.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Coronavirus &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Run, don’t walk&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Chaguan | A people’s war</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Chaguan%20%20A%20people%E2%80%99s%20war/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Chaguan%20%20A%20people%E2%80%99s%20war/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T17:56:08.623Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T18:17:35.438Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020<br><br><br><font size="5"><b>Chaguan | A people’s war</b></font></p><p><i>China’s Communist rulers see a chance to mobilise the masses behind the party</i><br>Asked to craft a metaphor for all that the world admires and fears about modern China, a novelist could hardly improve on the coronavirus hospitals now rising, at fantastic speeds, in disease-stricken cities. Start with admiration. These construction sites are a ﬁne example of decisive Communist Party action. Work had been under way for two days when Chaguan visited the Second People’s Hospital in Changde, a city in the central province of Hunan, 400km from the epidemic’s suspected birthplace in Wuhan. Half a dozen excavators roared and pawed at the rust-red ground. A road-roller ﬂattened a gravel pad on which, by February 15th, a 200bed fever hospital is due to stand. </p><p>Yet if China’s resolve impresses outsiders, the dark side of oneparty rule also stands exposed. Changde must prepare for the worst in part because the authorities in Wuhan and the surrounding province of Hubei, Hunan’s neighbour, hid the virus’s impact for weeks. A desire to earn trust and avoid Wuhan’s fate probably explains why city-level propaganda oﬃcials in Changde—when this reporter was suddenly handed over to them by jumpy rural ofﬁcials and police—granted unusual access to the new hospital. </p><p>The construction site is overlooked by an ageing hospital block which, at the time of writing, houses 62 conﬁrmed cases. The whole hospital, emptied of ordinary patients and ringed by guards and warning signs, will soon have room for between 370 and 850 patients, depending on how many need strict isolation. It will serve Changde’s roughly 6m residents, who are divided between an urban centre and outlying rural counties. Oﬃcials say they hope not to need all the extra beds. </p><p>China’s pop-up hospitals do not merely awe foreigners. They have become a staple of domestic propaganda, with state media pumping out tales of building workers and medics labouring to the point of collapse. For all that, when trying to assess how this crisis may aﬀect the party, it is a mistake to focus narrowly on topdown actions. For the party is also bent on a task that is less familiar to outsiders but central to how China works at times of stress: mobilising the masses, nationwide. </p><p>Some techniques hark back to Mao’s time. Grassroots party members are busy scolding and reporting neighbours who defy orders to stay indoors and avoid social gatherings. In some regions villageloudspeakers, which in the days of collective farms blared out slogans, patriotic songs and injunctions to work harder, have crackled back to life. </p><p>Public opinion is hard to gauge in authoritarian China. In Fuqingshan village, perched amid strawberry farms outside Changde, locals describe how they watch for anyone arriving from Hubei and generally “dissuade people from wandering around”. Then their party secretary arrives on a moped to ban further interviews, declaring: “There is no infectious disease here.” Elsewhere villagers, of their own volition, refer to virus-control as a battle in which all are enlisted: a “people’s war”, as the party now calls it. </p><p>Until January the pole-mounted loudspeakers that loom over Chen Hongxia’s home in Guanyin village were mostly quiet, broadcasting only a news bulletin each evening. Now they blare out hours of virus-control information from eight each morning. Ms Chen, 41, concedes that the “very noisy” broadcasts make it hard for her son, who is eight, to study at home. As she speaks, an ampliﬁed voice recites rules against hunting or selling wild animals for meat. A cancer patient for two years, wearing padded pink pyjamas on a brief foray outdoors, Ms Chen stands out for not wearing one of the face masks that all Chinese are meant to wear outside, though stocks are running low. “I can’t ﬁnd anywhere to buy a mask. But what should I do? I just stay at home,” she explains, as her son scampers up to join her. Asked whether the state or the masses are responsible for beating the coronavirus, she answers: both. “China has a huge population. If you ask me who I should depend on, I think I need to depend on myself,” she ventures. At the same time, she adds, the government has “a good understanding of the big picture, which individuals are incapable of”.</p><br><b>Passing the buck to the grassroots </b><p>There are 99 party members in nearby Luluoping, a village of over 3,000 people. Guo Linlin is one of them. Locals are fearful, she admits, because “the situation is becoming more severe”. Her work of reassurance includes watching 14 villagers who returned from jobs in Hubei during the recent lunar new year, who must remain indoors, shun visitors and have their temperatures taken twice a day. This work leans on a “grid management” system which divides the village in two. Further subdivisions are monitored by oﬃcials and volunteers, some of them elderly folk in special red-and-gold disease-control armbands. A notice in the village listing new rules imposed by the local county, Taoyuan, concludes: “We invite the masses to supervise implementation.” </p><p>Mass mobilisation has a dark history in China. Majoritarianism is a temptation in a big and quarrelsome country because of its power to unite people against a suspect minority. Shamefully, local oﬃcials have been tolerating prejudice and vigilantism against migrants with identity papers from Hubei, even if they have not been there for months (reports and online videos abound of Wuhan folk being barred from hotels or sealed in their own homes behind front doors blocked with metal poles or chains). </p><p>Blaming external foes is a temptation, too. Chinese diplomats and state media have eagerly accused America of unfairly barring travellers from China—though numerous countries have imposed similar restrictions. China’s internet is full of conspiracy theories about the cia creating the coronavirus to keep China down. It is tempting to shrug when Chinese oﬃcials play such politics. What really counts, surely, is building hospitals and saving lives? But to China’s rulers, politics is never play. Every crisis is a chance to strengthen the party’s grip. A virus is no exception.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chaguan | A people’s war&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;China’s Communist rulers se
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The world this week</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/The%20world%20this%20week/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/The%20world%20this%20week/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T17:46:20.875Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T18:29:28.669Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020<br><br><br><font size="5"><b>The world this week </b>Politics</font></p><p><font color="red"><b>The Wuhan ban </b></font><br>The number of infections and deaths from the Wuhan virus continued to rise. More than 99% of the cases are in China. Several countries, including America and Australia, banned the entry of non-citizens who have recently visited China. Hong Kong announced that visitors from the Chinese mainland would have to undergo quarantine for 14 days; medical workers went on strike, calling for a complete closure of the Hong Kong mainland border. A Chinese diplomat accused other countries of over-reacting by barring travellers from China.</p><br><font size="5"><b>The world this week </b>Business</font><p>The coronavirus crisis in China unnerved the country’s stock markets. The CSI index fell by 8% in a day, its worst performance since August 2015, before rebounding somewhat. As an emergency measure China’s central bank injected extra liquidity into the ﬁnancial system, the biggest such one-day intervention since 2004, and cut some interest rates. Macau closed its casinos for two weeks. </p><p>China is the linchpin in the supply chains of many global manufacturers, but the disruption from the coronavirus lockdown has been most acute in the motor industry. Hyundai halted production at its factories in South Korea because it couldn’t get components from China. Many foreign carmakers in China extended the Chinese new year break and kept their plants closed. </p><p>Keeping to one of its pledges in the “phase one” trade deal with America, China’s government said it would cut tariﬀs on $75bn-worth of American exports. Some said the announcement was timed to cheer the markets. China is also committed to make extensive purchases of American goods under phase one, but that could be diﬃcult amid the coronavirus outbreak.</p><p>The price of oil fell sharply, in part because demand from Chinese industry and international airlines is expected to drop because of the Wuhan virus. OPEC and Russia met to discuss emergency cuts to output that could shore up prices. BP said that the outbreak could reduce projected global growth in oil demand this year by up to 40%. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;The world this week &lt;/b&gt;Politics&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;The W
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Keep out</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Keep%20out/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Keep%20out/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T17:41:48.971Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T17:45:29.898Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020<br><br><br><font color="red"><b>Hong Kong and the mainland</b></font><br><font size="5"><b>Keep out</b></font></p><p><font size="0.5">HONG KONG</font><br><b>The coronavirus is fuelling tensions in a protest-racked city</b><br>“There is noreason for measures that unnecessarily interfere with international travel and trade.” So declared the World Health Organisation’s chief, Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, on February 3rd after several countries, to prevent the spread of the coronavirus, had closed their borders with China or (like America and Australia) announced that foreign citizens who had recently visited China would be barred from entering. Yet many people in Hong Kong want the territory to seal itself oﬀ from the Chinese mainland. Their demands are putting new political pressure on the territory’s leader, Carrie Lam, after months of pro-democracy unrest. As The Economist went to press, 21people in Hong Kong had been detected with the virus, of whom seven were from the mainland. Six of the others were Hong Kong residents who caught it while travelling in China. They included a man whose death, attributed to the virus, was announced on February 4th. It was the ﬁrst such fatality in the territory and only the second outside the Chinese mainland (the other was in the Philippines). The remaining eight cases involved infections that occurred in Hong Kong itself. </p><p>Mrs Lam has responded with evertighter controls. On January 27th visitors from Hubei, the province where the virus was discovered, were banned from entering Hong Kong. On January 30th six of 14 border checkpoints were closed. Hong Kongers who had travelled to Hubei were ordered into quarantine centres. The mainland’s government also imposed restrictions, stopping the issuing of permits for tourist trips to Hong Kong. The number of mainlanders arriving at border posts<br>other than the airport fell by 90% compared with two weeks earlier. Mrs Lam said that closing the border entirely would be “discriminatory”, but four days later she announced that remaining entry points, apart from the airport, two road bridges and a cruise terminal, would be closed from February 4th. On February 5th she announced that anyone arriving from the mainland would be quarantined for 14 days and the cruise terminal would be shut. </p><p>For some Hong Kongers, these measures have not been enough. On February 3rd around 3,000 non-essential medical staﬀ working in public hospitals went on indeﬁnite strike—the biggest such action in the health system’s history. Their demands include the full closure of the border. The following day their ranks swelled to 7,000. They have vowed to continue their strike, despite Mrs Lam’s measures. </p><p>She is in murky political water. The strikers belong to a recently formed union with links to activists who have been at the forefront of the anti-government unrest that has roiled the territory since June. Other pro-democracy unions have threatened to join them, including one for bus drivers. </p><p>The central government, however, would not be happy with a total ban. It accused America of sowing fear when it became the ﬁrst country to barforeign travellers coming from China. China’s acting ambassador to Israel compared such controls to the turning away of Jewish refugees during the Holocaust. The embassy later apologised, saying there was “no intention whatsoever to compare the dark days of the Holocaust with the current situation”.</p><p>But many Hong Kongers are fearful. Memories are still fresh of SARS in 2003, a disease caused by another coronavirus discovered in China. That outbreak infected about 1,750 people in Hong Kong and killed almost 300. Mrs Lam, not least, will be mindful of events that year. Public anger over the government’s perceived hesitancy in handling SARS fuelled unrest caused by a proposed national-security bill. The crisis eventually prompted the central government to replace Tung Chee-hwa, Hong Kong’s ﬁrst post-colonial leader. </p><p>Mrs Lam appears to have retained the central government’s backing during the past few months of turmoil on Hong Kong’s streets. But in a territory where distrust of the government runs deep, it is unlikely that her response to the new coronavirus will boost her abysmal ratings at home.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hong Kong and the mainland&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Keep out&lt;/b
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Under observation</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Under%20observation/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/18/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8A%E4%B8%8E%E6%96%B0%E5%86%A0%E7%97%85%E6%AF%92%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E%E7%9B%B8%E5%85%B3%E7%9A%84%E6%96%87%E7%AB%A0/Under%20observation/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T17:18:28.484Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T18:16:50.258Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020<br><br><br><font color="red"><b>The Wuhan virus</b></font><br><font size="5"><b>Under observation</b></font></p><p><font size="0.5">BEIJING</font><br><b>A weak health-care system complicates China’s battle with the coronavirus</b></p><p>The doctors who examined Rana Zhou’s parents decided that the couple had probably caught the coronavirus which has been sweeping their home city, Wuhan, and spreading globally. But they said they did not have enough test kits to be sure. Instead of ﬁnding them beds in a hospital, oﬃcials in their neighbourhood told them to go to one of many hotels which the government has requisitioned in order to monitor and isolate people with minor virus-related symptoms. But when her father’s fever worsened, staﬀ said they could not take care of him. They told the pair they would have to return home. </p><p>It is a scary time to be ill in Wuhan. The city has one-third of all conﬁrmed infections by the virus and three-quarters of the deaths caused by it. People there are barred from travelling elsewhere (similar rules apply across Hubei, a Syria-sized province of which Wuhan is the capital). Since late January military medics have been piling into the city. Soldiers are helping enforce its cordons. The army’s growing presence reassures many people, says a resident. But some ﬁnd it unnerving. </p><p>With hospitals brimming, the local government has announced new rules. Rather than visiting hospitals, people who think they might have the virus should tell district oﬃcials about their symptoms and seek examinations at local clinics—facilities which, in normal times, many people eschew in favour of what they regard as the hospitals’ more professional care. Wuhan has opened makeshift hospitals in an exhibition centre and a sports arena to house patients who are only mildly ill from the virus. Elsewhere in China health services are also under strain, even if the pressure is less than in Hubei. Oﬃcials in many places have banned non-essential hospital visits to avoid contagion. But many people, afraid of catching the virus, now avoid hospitals anyway, except in emergencies. </p><p>China’s health system can cope better with shocks than in 2003 during the sars outbreak. At that time, oﬃcials feared that the spread of the virus might be hidden because rural residents, lacking health insurance, would avoid hospitals. The government tried to allay such concerns by oﬀering free treatment for sars. Since then it has considerably expanded access to state-funded insurance schemes. More than 95% of Chinese are now covered. Outof-pocket payments have fallen from about 60% of medical expenses to 30%. But for poorer people, the costs can still be crippling. The government recently promised that it would pay for all treatment related to the new virus. That was too late for a pregnant woman infected in Wuhan. She died after her husband decided he could no longer aﬀord the bill, according to a doctor there interviewed by Caixin, a magazine. The policy changed the next day.</p><br><b>Barely better than barefoot</b><p>The government has spent lavishly on infrastructure, but its investment in health care has failed to keep up. China says it has about 2.6 doctors for every 1,000 people, higher than the average for middle-income countries. But the World Health Organisation says half of China’s doctors do not have a bachelor’s degree. Among those in villages and small towns, only 10-15% do. Some practise traditional Chinese medicine, a form of treatment that has government approval but little scientiﬁc basis (stocks of an oral liquid based on such medicine have been ﬂying oﬀ shelves since a recent report by Xinhua, an oﬃcial news agency, that it can “suppress” the virus). There is also an acute shortage of nurses. The average in rich countries is three per doctor. In China it is only one. </p><p>China’s investment in health care has mostly gone to big hospitals in cities. Wuhan has about half of Hubei’s best medical facilities, but only about one-ﬁfth of the province’s population. Far less attention has been paid to primary-care clinics, which in more developed systems handle minor ailments and escalate the rest to specialists. Only about 5% of China’s registered doctors serve as general practitioners. The average in the OECD, a club mostly of rich countries, is 23%. After Wuhan imposed a lockdown in late January, panicky residents converged on large hospitals seeking reassurance. The queues would have promoted cross-infection, says Xi Chen of Yale University. </p><p>Public anger about health care, including the gouging of patients by hospitals, has triggered occasional violence against doctors. In late January a man attacked medical staﬀ in Wuhan after his father-in-law died from the virus. But the system’s public image may have improved during the current crisis. Many people praise doctors’willingness to join theﬁght in Hubei, despite high rates of infection among medical workers there. They will need such support in the struggle ahead.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;来源：The Economist：February 8th 2020&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Wuhan virus&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Under observation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>测试</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/17/test/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/17/test/</id>
    <published>2020-02-17T12:02:56.410Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T13:47:22.894Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="测试"><a href="#测试" class="headerlink" title="测试"></a>测试</h1><h2 id="代码显示测试"><a href="#代码显示测试" class="headerlink" title="代码显示测试"></a>代码显示测试</h2><figure class="highlight c"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br><span class="line">19</span><br><span class="line">20</span><br><span class="line">21</span><br><span class="line">22</span><br><span class="line">23</span><br><span class="line">24</span><br><span class="line">25</span><br><span class="line">26</span><br><span class="line">27</span><br><span class="line">28</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="meta">#<span class="meta-keyword">include</span> <span class="meta-string">&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="function"><span class="keyword">int</span> <span class="title">main</span><span class="params">()</span></span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="function"></span>&#123;</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">int</span> k=<span class="number">0</span>,t;</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="built_in">scanf</span>(<span class="string">"%d"</span>,&amp;t);</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">if</span>(t&gt;<span class="number">10</span>) <span class="keyword">return</span> <span class="number">0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">while</span>(k&lt;t)</span><br><span class="line">    &#123;</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="keyword">int</span> n;</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="built_in">scanf</span>(<span class="string">"%d"</span>,&amp;n);</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="keyword">if</span>(n&lt;<span class="number">1</span>||n&gt;<span class="number">100</span>) <span class="keyword">break</span>;</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="keyword">int</span> a[<span class="number">100</span>];</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="keyword">int</span> i;</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="keyword">for</span>(i=<span class="number">0</span>;i&lt;n;i++)</span><br><span class="line">        &#123;</span><br><span class="line">            <span class="built_in">scanf</span>(<span class="string">"%d"</span>,&amp;a[i]);</span><br><span class="line">        &#125;</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="keyword">float</span> count1=<span class="number">0</span>,count0=<span class="number">0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="keyword">for</span>(i=<span class="number">0</span>;i&lt;n;i++)</span><br><span class="line">        &#123;</span><br><span class="line">            <span class="keyword">if</span>(a[i]==<span class="number">1</span>) count1+=<span class="number">1.0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">            <span class="keyword">else</span> <span class="keyword">if</span>(a[i]==<span class="number">0</span>) count0+=<span class="number">1.0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">        &#125;</span><br><span class="line">        <span class="built_in">printf</span>(<span class="string">"%.2f\n"</span>,count1/(count1+count0));</span><br><span class="line">        k++;</span><br><span class="line">    &#125;</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">return</span> <span class="number">0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="图片显示测试"><a href="#图片显示测试" class="headerlink" title="图片显示测试"></a>图片显示测试</h2><p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wintersakurako/wintersakurako.github.io/master/shawu_s.jpg" alt="纱雾" title="纱雾"></p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wintersakurako/wintersakurako.github.io/master/shawu_s.jpg" width="50%"><h2 id="文字显示测试"><a href="#文字显示测试" class="headerlink" title="文字显示测试"></a>文字显示测试</h2><p>Activity Trackers May Undermine Weight Loss Efforts</p><p>Wearable activity monitors can count your steps and track your movements, but they dont, apparently, help you lose weight. In fact, you might lose more weight without them.</p><p>The fascinating finding comes from a study published today in JAMA that found dieting adults who wore activity monitors for 18 months lost significantly fewer pounds over that time than those who did not.</p><p>The results suggest that activity monitors may not change our behavior in the way we expected, and raise interesting questions about the tangled relationships between exercise, eating, our willpower and our waistlines.</p><p>There have been tantalizing hints in a few studies recently that new technologies such as wearable activity monitors, which tell us how much we are moving and how many calories we have burned during the day, might help some people to drop pounds.</p><p>Those studies, however, had typically been small scale and short term, so it was still unclear how much activity monitors might aid in weight loss.</p><p>So for the new study, University of Pittsburgh scientists from the Physical Activity and Weight Management Research Center and their colleagues gathered almost 500 young, overweight men and women who wanted to lose weight. The recruits ranged in age from 18 to 35 since, presumably, these younger volunteers would be familiar with and competent using technologies such as activity trackers and any learning curve would be slight.</p><p>The volunteers were weighed and their general health and fitness assessed.</p><p>Then, for the first six months of the study, the volunteers followed a straightforward, low-calorie diet designed to provide steady weight loss and were urged to start moving more, aiming for at least 100 minutes of moderate activity each week. They kept daily food and exercise diaries and attended weekly counseling sessions.</p><p>By the end of six months, everyone had lost weight. And then the actual experiment began.</p><p>The scientists now divided their volunteers in half. One group was told to start logging their daily exercise sessions onto a study website.</p><p>The others were given a monitor designed to be worn on the upper arm that would track their physical activity and provide feedback about whether they were achieving goals for step counts, calorie expenditure and so on.</p><p>We were pretty confident that the volunteers in the group using the activity monitors would exercise more, monitor their calorie intake better, and lose more weight than the people in the self-monitoring group, says John Jakicic, a distinguished professor in the department of health and physical activity at the University of Pittsburgh and the studys lead author.</p><p>For 18 months, the volunteers logged into the study website or wore the monitor on most days. Counselors occasionally checked with everyone by phone and sent encouraging text messages.</p><p>After 18 months  and two years after the beginning of the study  all of the volunteers returned to the lab to repeat their measurements from the start.</p><p>Most were thinner now than at the start of the study (although many had regained some of the weight that they had lost during the first six months).</p><p>Those who had not worn activity monitors were, on average, about 13 pounds lighter now than two years ago.</p><p>Those who had worn the monitors, however, weighed only about 8 pounds less than at the start.</p><p>We were definitely surprised, Dr. Jakicic says.</p><p>The reasons for the difference in weight loss are not immediately clear, he says.</p><p>Theoretically, those using the monitors might have been so inspired to exercise that they moved a lot, developed large appetites, and overate, blunting any weight loss from the workouts, he says.</p><p>But in fact, the data from the monitors shows that those wearing the technology generally exercised less than those in the other group.</p><p>So perhaps the monitors resulted in less motivation to move, Dr. Jakicic says. It is possible, he says, that when those wearing the trackers realized they would not reach their daily exercise goal, they simply gave up, leading to relatively low caloric expenditure on those days, and less weight loss overall than among those not using the technology.</p><p>The people using the monitors may also have assumed that, in some roundabout way, the technology removed responsibility from them for monitoring their energy intake, Dr. Jakicic says. People may have focused on the technology and forgotten to focus on their behaviors and ate too much, he says.</p><p>Dr. Jakicic and his colleagues hope to conduct follow-up studies that will directly examine how activity monitors affect exercise motivation and subsequent weight loss.</p><p>What these results say to me is that we still have a great deal to learn about how monitoring technologies affect real-life actions, Dr. Jakicic says. Peoples responses to a monitor strapped to their arm may not always be rational and could result in behaviors that are the opposite of those that the monitor would be expected to encourage.</p><p>In other words, we humans are strange and often our own worst enemies, especially when it comes to trying to increase our exercise or reduce our weight.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;测试&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#测试&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;测试&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;测试&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;代码显示测试&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#代码显示测试&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;代码显示测试&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;代
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>成功啦！我爱这个世界！</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/17/hello-nihao/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/17/hello-nihao/</id>
    <published>2020-02-16T20:17:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-16T20:21:39.892Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/17/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/17/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2020-02-16T19:34:37.106Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-17T16:56:45.266Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Welcome-to-Hexo-This-is-your-very-first-post-Check-documentation-for-more-info-If-you-get-any-problems-when-using-Hexo-you-can-find-the-answer-in-troubleshooting-or-you-can-ask-me-on-GitHub"><a href="#Welcome-to-Hexo-This-is-your-very-first-post-Check-documentation-for-more-info-If-you-get-any-problems-when-using-Hexo-you-can-find-the-answer-in-troubleshooting-or-you-can-ask-me-on-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Welcome to Hexo! This is your very first post. Check documentation for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in troubleshooting or you can ask me on GitHub."></a>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a>.</h2><h1 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h1><h1 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h1><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">"My New Post"</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Writing</a></p><h1 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h1><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Server</a></p><h1 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h1><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Generating</a></p><h1 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h1><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h2 id=&quot;Welcome-to-Hexo-This-is-your-very-first-post-Check-documentation-for-more-info-If-you-get-any-problems-when-using-Hexo-you-can-find-
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
